A place you leave is a place that lives forever.
The Lost City is a drama, romance, history film directed by Andy Garcia.
In Havana, Cuba in the late 1950's, a wealthy family, one of whose sons is a prominent nightclub owner, is caught in
the violent transition from the oppressive regime of Batista to the Marxist government of Fidel Castro.
Castro's regime ultimately leads the nightclub owner to flee to New York.
Fico Fellove, played by Andy Garcia.
Don Donoso Fellove, played by Richard Bradford.
Luis Fellove, played by Nestor Carbonell.
Ricardo Fellove, played by Enrique Murciano.
Mercedes Fellove, played by Dominik Garcia.
Meyer Lansky, played by Dustin Hoffman.
The Lost City is a 2005 American drama film
directed and co-produced by Andy García.
It stars García, Dustin Hoffman, Inés Sastre and Bill Murray.
The film depicts the story of Fico Fellove, a wealthy nightclub owner in Havana
and his family whose lives are disrupted by the Cuban Revolution.
Attempting to remain apolitical, Fellove's family becomes divided when his brothers
join the Marxist rebels in their fight against the Batista regime.
The film was a passion project for García, who immigrated from Cuba to Miami at the start
of Fidel Castro's rule, and had been trying to make the film for 16 years.
It was filmed in the Dominican Republic instead of Cuba, as García was
denied entry to the country due to his criticism of Castro.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, who criticized the
screenplay, direction and the depiction of historical events.
It bombed at the box office, making $4.4 million on a $9.6 million budget.
The film explores themes of cuba, che guevara, fidel castro.
The tone is dark and emotional.